(Watch on KonFlix.vip)
I don't want to do the dance.
Then ask to be removed.
But that just doesn't fit my image.
But apparently, Nobunaga
actually ran away from a battle once.
But I don't think it's lame.
It's kind of cool how
he bares all his weaknesses, huh?
Saku,
‎PREVIOUSLY ON ‎TATSUKI: TOO KIND FOR SCHOOL
you can become Nobunaga too.
Saku! Go! You can do it!
Yeah!
Tatsuki! Sora jumped.
YUKANAI
IT'S ALMOST SUMMER VACATION!
WE WILL BE OPEN DURING SUMMER VACATION
I will give you this award to honor
your achievements
this past month.
-Here are some beads.
-Check.
Oh, you got me.
Hey.
I've been wondering for a while,
but who's that man?
Oh, that's Mr. Eiraku.
He comes every now and then
to teach us all sorts of old-school games.
He's not a strong player though,
so he’s pretty popular.
I see.
All right, it's time to clean up!
We're in the middle of a good game,
so give us some time.
But it's cleaning day.
Meanie.
Oh no, the paint dripped.
Oh no.
It was turning out so well too.
What a shocking failure.
-Shock-man.
-It's okay. Let me see it.
I'll show you how to fix it.
And then…
Go like this.
-Wow.
-It's so pretty.
Everyone, it's almost time to clean up.
Whoa, the demon is here.
What?
Who are you calling a demon?
-So scary!
-Oh no!
Come on.
-Start cleaning up.
-Seiryu.
Here. How about this?
Wow.
-It's amazing.
-Right?
Let's add more color--
Hurry up and clean!
Run, everyone! Run!
Don't let her catch you!
It says that
there's going to be a barbecue.
This is the schedule
for the summer vacation.
Make sure you hand it to your mom and dad.
-I'm so excited for this.
-Me too!
Bye.
-Bye.
Be careful.
-Hello.
-Bye.
Sorry I'm late.
-Ms. Tachibana, you're here for a meeting?
-Yes.
Sorry to make you wait.
-Hello.
Mr. Tatsuki.
-What?
-You've got paint on your face.
You've got paint on you.
-It's still there.
-Forget it.
How is Nene doing?
Well,
I'd like to cancel
her enrollment after this month.
Is that right?
Yes.
Lately, my daughter isn't keen
on coming here anymore.
Whether she wants to come or not
is entirely up to her, so that's okay,
but is she unwell or something?
No, not really.
She pretty much
stays holed up in her room,
but she somehow manages to make it
to cram school and piano lessons.
I see.
So when she's not at those places,
she stays in her room?
Yes.
I just don't want her to end up
as a shut-in.
That's worrisome, isn't it?
Yes.
But you know, maybe she's enjoying
being a shut-in.
-What?
-Enjoying it?
Yes.
We actually have lots of events
coming up this month,
so please let Nene know.
-Okay, will do.
-Thank you.
-Thank you for your time.
I can see myself out.
-Thank you.
-Take care.
See you again.
How does one enjoy being a shut-in?
What?
You don't know?
I'm heading out now.
Don't forget about
your piano lesson today.
NENE
-Here you go.
-Thank you.
Mr. Sora Fujinaga
was discharged this morning.
What?
-Is that right?
-Yes.
YUKANAI SUMMER VACATION EVENT
DIAMOND ART
LOTS OF DIFFERENT DESIGNS TO CHOOSE FROM!
-What's this?
-Where are you, Shi-chan?
-Wait, I'm scared.
-Where are you?
-I found you!
-Wait!
-There she is!
-Hold on!
-Shi-chan, you're so bad at this.
I wasn't able to do anything yet.
-You have to attack.
-Who's playing next?
I thought I was attacking.
Tatsuki is super strong.
Tatsuki is crazy good.
Really?
Hi, Nene.
Hello Nene.
Hello.
-You're so hyper.
-Kurumi, you're so fast.
I am, huh?
I'm always fast.
Hey Nene.
We just started.
Come join us.
Sit here.
Okay.
You can start
by placing the gems
on the mane and the tail.
-You can't be sloppy with this.
-I'm intent on finishing this.
-You're so detailed.
-Which gems do I use?
Yeah, it's so pretty.
Whichever one you want.
You're right.
Yeah.
Tatsuki, can you choose for me?
Then…
You can use the example as a reference.
-This pink color is so cute.
-Yeah.
Here you go.
Nene, will you be at the Yukanai Camp?
Camp?
Apparently, we're going to barbecue
and do fireworks together.
-That sounds like fun.
-Right?
You should come.
-Although we'll be staying the night here.
-Yeah.
That's not so bad.
But this is my last month here.
Really?
That's a bummer.
Yeah.
Oh no, I messed up.
I did too. Look at mine.
-It's not aligned.
-Right?
Oh no.
Wow Nene, you're so good.
-Very nice.
-Looks good.
-Yeah.
-You're so good.
But what color should I choose
for the horse?
You can choose whatever you want.
I chose green for mine.
That's very you, Mao.
It's so pretty.
I think I'll go with purple.
-Nice.
-That'll look cool.
Nene, what's your favorite color?
My favorite color…
I have to head to my piano lesson.
You can finish this next time.
But this is her last month, right?
If she wants to come,
she can come again next month. Okay?
Bye.
YUKANAI
Diamond art, huh?
Yeah.
They look good.
This is
the one that Nene Tachibana
was working on.
That's the girl that's leaving this month?
Yes.
It's detailed and precise.
She plays the piano, so she seems
to be good with her hands.
I see.
What did you think when you saw this?
Well…
I felt like…
it's really constrained.
Constrained?
I told her to freely choose the gems,
but she had a hard time deciding.
I wonder why that is.
Maybe
she's scared to express herself
freely and as she pleases?
She might be lacking self-confidence.
-What is it?
-Oh.
Watching Nene
reminded me of Sora for some reason.
How's your son doing?
It seems like he was discharged
from the hospital.
That's all I know.
-I see.
-Yeah.
Tatsuki, you need a good night's rest.
-Okay?
-Yeah.
The competition is coming up soon.
How's it going?
Do you think
you can do pretty well this time?
Not sure.
Your teacher said you'll do well
if you keep up the good work.
But I'm not as good as Big Sis.
There's no need
to compare yourself to her.
After all, you're you.
-Okay?
-Okay.
I went to Yukanai today.
What?
Why?
I did some diamond art.
Is that right?
Nene,
I've signed you up
for the summer study camp.
-What?
The cram school study camp?
Yeah.
You didn't do well
on that practice test the other day.
There's no need to pressure her
about it right now.
If she doesn't make up ground
during summer break,
she'll fall behind.
She hasn't even been able to go to school.
I don't want to push her too hard
with things like study camp.
Then
is it okay if her grades keep dropping?
The piano competition is coming up soon,
so I want her to focus on that right now.
You prefer that too, right Nene?
It's better to focus on her studies.
-Is it really so?
-What about the entrance exam?
She won't take it?
That's not what I'm saying.
Nene.
What do you want to do?
YUKANAI
NOW ACCEPTING NEW STUDENTS
Hey!
Anybody there?
-What?
-Coming.
-Help me.
-I'm coming.
-I'll help.
-Here.
What's all this?
They're tents
for the Yukanai Camp next week!
I had some extras at home in storage.
Camping is all about the tent, right?
Just pitching them in the yard
will really set the mood.
Yeah.
I guess we need to start
making preparations too.
Right.
We have to get ingredients
for the barbecue.
-I want to do fireworks too.
-Sounds fun.
What will you do, Ajicchan?
Sweets workshop.
We're planning to make ice cream together.
That sounds fun. What about you, Soya?
I'll be doing
a late-night gaming tournament.
I'm seriously going to win.
I will be in charge of stargazing.
There are lots of participants this year,
so I'm looking forward to it!
I don't see Nene these days,
but is she coming?
She'll be leaving
at the end of this month.
I see.
I'll try to at least
extend another invitation.
Maybe I'll ask Shi-chan
to be the camp leader this year.
Do you think I can handle
such an important role?
-Shouldn't it be Mr. Tatsuki instead?
-No.
Tatsuki isn't cut out
for that kind of stuff.
Then
Mr. Tatsuki,
-you're in charge of the barbecue.
-Huh?
What do I have to do?
Buy the ingredients,
then prepare and cook
on the day of the event.
-We'll be counting on you.
-I have to do that alone?
Yes.
-What?
-Good luck.
That'll be impossible!
Hello, this is Tachibana.
This is Aomine from Yukanai.
-Hello.
-Um…
An event called Yukanai Camp
is coming up, can Nene attend
before she leaves at the end of the month?
I'm sorry.
She's going to be at a study camp
on that day.
I see.
-Thank you for your time.
-Thank you.
Um…
How has Nene been doing lately?
She's doing well.
I'm glad to hear that.
Thank you for your time. Bye.
Bye.
Nene?
-Tatsuki.
-Off to your piano lesson?
-I have cram school today.
-I see.
What were you doing?
I'm out shopping
to buy things for our camp.
It's so heavy my arms are about
to fall off.
I wish I could go.
You should come.
But I didn't sign up.
You can still come.
You can finish the diamond art.
But
I have to go to the study camp too.
I see.
EXAM PREP CRAM SCHOOL
Bye.
See you again.
Nene.
Want to work on the diamond art?
Here you go.
Use whatever color gem you want.
Which color should I choose?
Do you have gold?
Gold?
I don't think so.
You like gold?
Yeah, since it represents number one.
I see.
Then
I'll make sure to buy it.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Can I take this home once I finish?
Of course.
Your mom and dad will be surprised
with your masterpiece.
But I'll get in trouble
for skipping cram school.
Really?
You used two different colors
for the horses, huh?
-Is it weird?
-No.
It's such a great idea.
Why did you choose these colors?
Mom likes pink,
and I think this other color
will make Dad happy.
That's nice.
I'm home.
Welcome back.
‎I'm done.
Nene,
why didn't you go to cram school?
They called to tell us you didn't show up.
I'm sorry.
Where've you been until now?
Yukanai.
Why?
What were you doing there?
We're fine with you going there,
but just know this,
you have responsibilities too.
I'm sorry.
I'm not asking
for anything difficult here.
If school isn't a good fit for you,
then it's fine that you don't go.
But in exchange, you need to go
to cram school and study.
You're taking the entrance exam, right?
And yet, if you go around saying
you can't do this and you can't do that,
that's being unreasonable, isn't it?
What do you plan to do from here on out?
Let's not get into that now.
Why not?
I'm saying this for her sake.
She can study
at her own pace
and do it little by little.
Things turned out this way
because you keep coddling her like that.
As if it's my fault?
You keep on pressuring her like that
all the time…
-So it's my fault?
-I didn't say that.
Stack small pieces of charcoal
in a pyramid atop the fire starter…
A pyramid?
We got a call from Nene's mom.
What did she say?
She was upset.
Were you aware
that Nene skipped cram school?
‎-Yeah.
‎-No wonder she was upset.
Nene didn't want to go,
so there's nothing I can do.
Yeah…
But even so, you should've
at least reported it.
Hey everyone.
-Hello.
-Hey.
-Here's what you asked for.
-Thank you.
Sixty colors should be enough, right?
More than enough.
By the way,
what happened to Nene after that?
She took the finished diamond art
home with her.
I found it.
Here it is.
-She chose the colors pink and brown?
-Yes.
‎She used brown and pink because
‎those are her parents' favorite colors.
But I guess
they're not Nene's favorite colors.
I wonder what this means.
She said that she likes the color gold.
But I wonder if she said that
with her parents in mind.
I see.
I wonder how she really feels about
leaving Yukanai.
Should I go
visit Nene at her house tomorrow?
It's better not to interfere too much
in other people's family matters.
I have no intention
of interfering unnecessarily.
Then why do you want to go there?
Because…
I just want to do whatever I can.
After all, Yukanai might be
a precious place for Nene.
Let's leave this up to Shi-chan for now.
But be careful when dealing with Nene.
Yes.
Thank you
for taking time to meet with me.
My pleasure.
But we still plan to leave Yukanai
at the end of this month.
I'm sorry.
No problem at all.
Where is Nene right now?
She's in her room.
I just want to let her be for now.
I think
she's a bit overwhelmed right now.
NENE
She's still going to cram school
and piano lessons, right?
Yes.
To be honest,
I feel like cram school
is quite a burden for her.
After all, she stopped going to school
because she didn't enjoy studying.
That’s why
I think she should focus on piano,
since that's something she enjoys.
Did Nene say that she enjoys it?
I can tell just by watching her.
I've decided
to take a leave of absence from work.
As a parent,
I intend to face this issue with her
and help her out.
So please rest assured.
I'm sorry,
-but can I use the restroom?
-Yes.
YU
I HEARD SORA WAS DISCHARGED,
BUT HOW'S HE DOING?
Hey Sora!
-Sora!
-Don't come in here!
Go away!
Open the door, Sora!
Shut up!
The study camp starts today, right?
It's almost time to go.
I wonder where she is.
Hey.
Are you ready to go?
I'm coming in.
What's the matter? Do you not feel well?
I'm okay.
I'll take you to the station.
Let's hurry.
Okay.
Do your best.
-Thanks.
-Sure.
CRAM SCHOOL
FOR MIDDLE SCHOOL ENTRANCE EXAMS
Good morning.
Yes.
YUKANAI
YUKANAI CAMP
All right.
Hello!
Hey!
Let's play Mario Kart.
There's a game in the evening.
I want to practice for that.
What?
You're using me just to practice?
-Don't forget.
-Attention!
Whoever's free, come out to the yard.
-Okay.
-Come help us.
This will fit about four to five.
This is exciting.
I've been wanting to do stargazing.
Do you know much about stars?
Not at all. I only know the North Star.
-I see.
-But
there are apps that can help us out.
I can search for the stars I want to see.
That's so handy.
The tent looks nice.
Oh, it's a telescope!
Yeah, Professor Mikumo brought this.
-Wow.
-Yeah.
I found it at a flea market.
Hey,
someone help me out.
I'll help.
Thanks, Umine.
Then
-can you bring the firewood?
-Firewood?
-Yeah.
-This?
Yeah, the same one.
Okay.
-Thanks.
-Tatsuki.
Can I do the fireworks?
Yeah, but it won't be as pretty
if you do it right now.
We can stay awake
as long as we want today, right?
Yup, as long as you want.
Then I'll stay awake all night.
People who say that
always fall asleep first.
Keep shaking.
All right.
Let's take it out of the bag.
-It's done!
-Wow!
Wow.
Let's all eat this tonight.
Hooray!
Begin.
Go!
Let's all eliminate Ei-chan first.
Good idea.
Don't bully the elderly.
Hey, did Nene show up?
Nope, she's not here.
I see.
-Thanks.
-Sure.
Go for it.
Go, go!
You can do it.
-You can do it.
What's wrong with this?
Just a little bit more.
We can't eat unless you get
the fire started.
-Just wait a minute.
-How's it going?
I piled the charcoal
in the form of a pyramid.
-But…
-Oh.
There's no way
air can pass through like this.
Huh?
You can do it.
All right. It's ready.
-Soya, you're a genius.
-Thank you.
Good job.
Okay.
All right, let's start grilling.
-It looks delicious.
-I can't wait to eat paella.
Ready?
Open sesame!
It's paella.
It looks so good.
It's so good!
It's super yummy!
I want to roast a marshmallow.
I'm going to grill a sausage.
-Go ahead.
-It's time
-to grill some corn!
-Yay!
It's time for corn.
Where did Tatsuki go?
Oh?
He ran away, huh?
Yup, he's not fit to be a leader at all.
The person you have called
is unable to answer right now…
YU
Hello.
I told you not to contact me anymore.
How's Sora?
How's he doing? Is he all right?
You know…
If you truly care about him,
stay away from us forever.
‎Hey.
This was made
with gems of my favorite color.
Tatsuki, you made this, right?
That reminds me!
Take a look at this.
Ta-da!
-It's beautiful.
-Isn't it?
Go ahead and use it.
I was supposed
to go to the cram school study camp today.
Good morning.
I'm sorry,
but I won't be going to the study camp.
You decided not to go?
I hate studying and playing the piano.
What?
I thought you liked piano.
I hate it.
I see.
It must've been tough for you.
Then,
let's take time to enjoy this later.
Let's enjoy the barbecue first.
Hurry or there'll be no meat left.
Let's go.
All right, let's get ready
to crack the watermelon open.
Here's another skewer.
-Take one, Nene.
-Thank you.
-Here you go.
-Thanks.
What? Oh no.
Oh no! It's stuck!
You can remove it using baking soda.
I need a different solution.
Go! Go!
Go! You can do it.
Yeah!
Let's try it.
It's so good.
It's really good.
BLUE FLAME
JAPAN BLUE
This one is so cute.
How pretty.
Your mom doesn't know you're here?
She thinks I'm at study camp.
That's not good.
-I'm going to call your mom.
-Wait.
Don't tell her.
But
your mom will be worried.
I don't want to go home.
Then you don't have to.
I'll discuss it with your mom.
Okay?
What? She didn't go to study camp?
Why?
I just got a call telling me
that she's at Yukanai.
-I'm going to go get her.
-Wait.
What?
There's a camping event
going on at Yukanai today, so she'll be
staying the night.
What do you mean?
As her parents
we should be going there to pick her up.
Fine.
But I'll go instead.
All right.
The one I did the other day…
Did your dad and mom like it?
I didn't show it to them.
I see.
What's the matter?
I worked so hard to make it,
but I ended up destroying it.
Even though I worked so hard on it.
Nene, what is it
that you want to do?
I don't know.
You can do whatever you want.
You're not going to use gold?
The truth is…
my favorite color is blue.
Okay.
YUKANAI
Good evening.
-Come in.
-Thank you.
Um…
she just fell asleep.
Can you take her back tomorrow?
I'm taking her back tonight.
Please wait a second.
-Nene is inside, right?
-Wait.
Nene is saying
that she doesn't want to go home.
What?
She would never say something like that.
That's probably because
she can't bring herself to tell you that.
She did a diamond art project.
I told her to freely choose
whatever color she wants,
but at first she would only try
to replicate the sample.
It made me wonder if she was too afraid
to express her own will.
Even when I told her
to choose any color she wanted,
she chose the brown that would make
her dad happy
and the pink that her mom would like.
What's the meaning behind that?
I believe she's trying to do everything
in order to please her parents.
Does anything come to mind?
My husband and I have discussions
about her quite often.
He wants to send her to cram school,
while I want her to take up the piano.
We do clash over our differing viewpoints…
But I personally believe
that the best approach is to simply let
Nene do whatever she wants to do.
And that it is my role as her parent
to help her cultivate those talents.
Her talents?
She loves playing the piano.
Nene.
I hate the piano.
I can never become as good as Big Sis,
and honestly,
I don't want to play the piano at all.
Then
-why didn't you say so?
-There's no way I could.
If I do, you and Dad
will start fighting again.
Why don't we let her stay here tonight?
No,
we've already canceled our enrollment,
so it's okay.
-But we don't mind at all--
-Tatsuki.
It's okay.
Are you sure?
I'll go home.
Sorry for bothering you late at night.
Go get changed.
Thank you.
It's worrisome, isn't it?
TACHIBANA
Nene, what's wrong?
Hey.
Nene. Nene, open up.
Mr. Tatsuki.
Mr. Tatsuki! It's about Nene…
‎What?
Thanks for coming.
No problem.
I don't know what to do anymore.
Don't come in here! Go away!
Sora! Open the door, Sora!
I
don't know what to do either.
What?
But…
I have to do something.
PREVIEW OF THE NEXT EPISODE
‎THIS DRAMA IS FICTION
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita